<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://agilesysadmin.github.io/</id>
    <title>agile sysadmin</title>
    <updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/index.atom" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/" rel="alternate" />
    <author>
        <name>Ferenc Erki</name>
    </author>
    <generator version="0.098">Statocles</generator>

    <entry>
        <id>https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2023/04/20/new-blog-who-dis/</id>
        <title>New blog, who dis?</title>
        <author><name>Ferenc Erki</name></author>
        <link href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2023/04/20/new-blog-who-dis/" rel="alternate" />
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
            <p>In the past months I kept tailoring essentially identical updates to various
platforms, like LinkedIn, Mastodon, and project-specific media. I also often
found myself explaining the same concepts and answering the same questions over
and over again.</p>

<p>It felt better to have a canonical source for my content, and keep the other
solutions as distribution channels. I also wished for a place to accommodate my
preferred authoring workflow for longer formats.</p>

<p>As a fresh start, I decided to migrate all the content from my previous <a href="https://agilesysadmin.wordpress.com/">Agile
sysadmin</a> blog to this site.</p>

<p>I expect to post soon more about the topics I’m most involved in or tools and
approaches I find most useful for my use cases. For example Rex, Perl, and
Gentoo, as well as automation, software delivery, testing, and open source.</p>



        ]]></content>
        <updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/11/16/aaphoto-is-available-in-gentoo/</id>
        <title>aaphoto is available in Gentoo</title>
        <author><name>Ferenc Erki</name></author>
        <link href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/11/16/aaphoto-is-available-in-gentoo/" rel="alternate" />
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
            <p>Auto Adjust Photo, or <a href="http://log69.com/aaphoto_en.html">aaphoto</a> in short, is a cool little tool for automatic color correction and resizing of photos. I cooked an ebuild for it a long time ago which was waiting to be rediscovered in a forgotten corner of my drive. After a quick refurbishing and some minor/trivial upstream cleanup with the extremely friendly author, it is now available in the main portage tree of Gentoo.</p>

<p>Thanks goes to:</p>

<ul>
<li>András Horváth for creating aaphoto</li>
<li>the always helpful Gentoo developers (in this particular case TomWij, mrueg and Pinkbyte) for their review via Bugzilla and #gentoo-dev-help, and for accepting me as a proxied maintainer for the package</li>
</ul>


                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/gentoo/">Gentoo</a>
                </p>

        ]]></content>
        <updated>2013-11-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <category term="Gentoo" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/09/09/simple-unattended-ubuntu-install-in-a-vm/</id>
        <title>Simple unattended Ubuntu install in a VM</title>
        <author><name>Ferenc Erki</name></author>
        <link href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/09/09/simple-unattended-ubuntu-install-in-a-vm/" rel="alternate" />
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
            <p>I wrote the <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/03/28/unattended-ubuntu-install-in-a-vm/">previous post about this topic</a> almost 6 months ago. Recently I had to review the process for a different project and I was curious if I could find an easier way to seed the installer options – preferably without modifying the original ISO file. Although there is more than one way to do it, I hope others would also find this method helpful.</p>

                <p><a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/09/09/simple-unattended-ubuntu-install-in-a-vm/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>

                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/kvm/">KVM</a>
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/ubuntu/">Ubuntu</a>
                </p>

        ]]></content>
        <updated>2013-09-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <category term="KVM" />
        <category term="Ubuntu" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/07/16/final-term-is-available-in-gentoo-sunrise/</id>
        <title>Final Term is available in Gentoo Sunrise</title>
        <author><name>Ferenc Erki</name></author>
        <link href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/07/16/final-term-is-available-in-gentoo-sunrise/" rel="alternate" />
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="http://finalterm.org/">Final Term</a> is an interesting and promising terminal emulator with advanced interactive features like semantic text menus, smart command completion, GUI terminal controls, reflow support and more.</p>

<p>I contributed an initial Hungarian translation for the project just to soon find myself hacking on an ebuild, and on minor features. All in all, as of 2013-07-11, Final Term is now available in Gentoo’s Sunrise overlay. You can find <a href="http://overlays.gentoo.org/proj/sunrise/">usage instructions here</a>.</p>

<p>Thanks to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Philipp Emanuel Weidmann for creating Final Term and <a href="http://blog.finalterm.org/">blogging about it</a></li>
<li>GitHub user Richard-W for letting me know that I’m not the only one who would like to use Final Term on Gentoo</li>
<li>Julian Ospald (hasufell) for reviewing my ebuilds, suggesting a modification to the build system, and finally merging the ebuild into Sunrise</li>
<li>the always helpful people on #gentoo-dev-help and #gentoo-sunrise</li>
</ul>


                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/ebuild/">ebuild</a>
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/final-term/">Final Term</a>
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/gentoo/">Gentoo</a>
                </p>

        ]]></content>
        <updated>2013-07-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <category term="ebuild" />
        <category term="Final Term" />
        <category term="Gentoo" />
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <id>https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/07/16/openwrt-support-in-r-ex/</id>
        <title>OpenWrt support in (R)?ex</title>
        <author><name>Ferenc Erki</name></author>
        <link href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/07/16/openwrt-support-in-r-ex/" rel="alternate" />
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="http://rexify.org/">(R)?ex</a> is a configuration management framework written in Perl which can be used to simplify and automate various system administrator tasks from deployment management to data center automation. <a href="https://openwrt.org/">OpenWrt</a> is a Linux distribution for embedded devices and it is widely used on different network equipment by replacing their original firmware. Soon you can combine the power of these two as OpenWrt support is coming into Rex!</p>

                <p><a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/2013/07/16/openwrt-support-in-r-ex/#section-2">Continue reading...</a></p>

                <p>Tags:
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/openwrt/">OpenWrt</a>
                    <a href="https://agilesysadmin.github.io/tag/rex/">Rex</a>
                </p>

        ]]></content>
        <updated>2013-07-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <category term="OpenWrt" />
        <category term="Rex" />
    </entry>
</feed>

